<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>

	<!--<info>
		<name>Weapons</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.8">
			<file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/dungeon-masters-guide/items/items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>-->
	
	<element name="Shadowsteel Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_SHADOWSTEEL_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>
				Forged in the heart of the Umbral Forge, the <em>Shadowsteel Sword</em> is a longsword infused with dark energies that draw strength from shadows. The blade absorbs ambient light, dimming its surroundings when drawn.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				The <em>Shadowsteel Sword</em> is a magic, sentient weapon that grants a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. When attacking a creature in dim light or darkness, the sword deals an additional 2d8 necrotic damage.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">While the sword is on your person, you gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, the range increases by 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				Once per long rest, as an action, you can cast <i>shadow blade</i> (save DC 16) from the sword. The sword regains the ability to cast this spell at the next dawn.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<i>
					<b>Sentience.</b>
				</i> The <em>Shadowsteel Sword</em> is a sentient neutral evil weapon with an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 18. It has darkvision out to a range of 120 feet and can communicate telepathically with its wielder.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<i>
					<b>Personality.</b>
				</i> The sword seeks to be wielded by those who walk in the shadows and thrive in the darkness. It encourages its wielder to shun the light and embrace the night, whispering temptations to seek power in darkness.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Dent's Greatsword" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_DENT_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>
				This <em>Greatsword</em> is a magical sword blessed by dumb barbarians.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				You have a +1 bonus to being gay.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">As a reaction when a creature within 5 feet of you takes damage, you can cry as a free action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
</elements>
