<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>

	<info>
		<name>Armours</name>
		<description>
			
		</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.25">
			<file name="items-armor.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/dungeon-masters-guide/items/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Engraved Monocle" type="Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MONOCLE_EMBLEM">
		<description>
			<p>
				A holy symbol etched into the form of a monocle to be worn by only the most stylish of Clerics and Paladins.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">—</set>
			<set name="container">Holy Symbol</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Veteran’s Cane" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_VETERAN_CANE">
		<description>
			<p>When you grasp this intricately carved Dwarven walking cane and use a bonus action to speak the command word, it transforms into an ordinary shortsword. Speaking this command word again converts it back into a cane</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">118</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Rockseeker Clan Token" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_FACTION_ROCKSEEKER_TOKEN">
		<description>
			<p>
				This small, weathered stone is intricately etched with the distinctive insignia of the Rockseeker Clan, depicting a pickaxe and a mountain, intertwined in a pattern that symbolises the clan's deep bond with the earth. 
				The stone’s surface feels surprisingly warm to the touch, as if imbued with the clan’s ancient energy.
			</p>

			<p>
				When you possess a Rockseeker Clan Token, it marks you as an ally of the Rockseeker Clan, granting you the following benefits:
			</p>

			<p>
				<list>
					<strong>Clan Recognition:</strong>  Members of the Rockseeker Clan recognise you immediately as a friend or trusted associate.
					This grants you advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks when interacting with any member of the clan, and they will generally be more willing to offer aid or information when asked.
				</list>
			</p>
			
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Faction, token, Rockseeker</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">150</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Used Bag of Holding" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_WHIZZ_HOLDING_BAG">
		<description>
			<p>
				This small, weathered bag of holding was previously enchanted by a great magic user. It was broken, seemingly by time and once again reforged by Whizz-Bang Rockseeker inside a lost Netherese crypt.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p class="indent">
				The bag can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 15 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires an action.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p class="indent">
				If the bag is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it ruptures and is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Astral Plane. 
				If the bag is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, but the bag must be put right before it can be used again. 
				Breathing creatures inside the bag can survive up to a number of minutes equal to 10 divided by the number of creatures (minimum 1 minute), after which time they begin to suffocate.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p class="indent">
				Placing a bag of holding inside an extradimensional space created by a handy haversack, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. 
				The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it to a random location on the Astral Plane. 
				The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.
			</p>
			
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Netherese, Bag of Holding, Rockseeker</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">150</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">15 lb</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Scroll of Forbidden Recursions" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_RECURSION">
		<description>
			<p>
				An old scroll from the Great Library, written in a tangled recursion of Draconic and Celestial.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<list>
					<li>When read aloud, the reader casts counterspell, dispel magic, or identify at 6th level, chosen at the time of reading.</li>
					<li>After use, the scroll disappears and the reader must make a DC 15 Wisdom save or suffer short-term madness for 1 minute, whispering truths they cannot comprehend.</li>
				</list>
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">scroll</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Bloodwell Vial" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_VIAL">
		<description>
			<p>
				To attune to this vial, you must place a few drops of your blood into it. The vial can’t be opened while your attunement to it lasts. If your attunement to the vial ends, 
				the contained blood turns to ash. You can use the vial as a spellcasting focus for your spells while wearing or holding it, and you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls and to the saving throw DCs of your sorcerer spells.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p class="indent">
				In addition, when you roll any Hit Dice to recover hit points while you are carrying the vial, you can regain 3 sorcery points. This property of the vial can’t be used again until the next dawn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sorcerer, spellcasting focus, sorcery points</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="sorcerer:spellcasting:attack" value="1"/>
			<stat name="sorcerer:spellcasting:dc" value="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Cape of the Manticore" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MANTI_SHIELD">
		<description>
			<p>
				Made from the manticore's hide and decorated with claw and fang motifs, the cloak has a faint magical shimmer. Once per day you may take the following reaction:
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<list>
					<strong>Tail Swipe (1 Charge):</strong> You may expend one of three charges to unleash the spikes of the cloak to lash out like a manticore's tail. 
					As a reaction the wearer can deal 1D6 bludgeoning damage to a creature within 5 feet that attacks them <strong>OR</strong> fly 10 feet away.
					This damage increases to 1D8 if the wearer falls below half health.
					
					The user may regain 1D3 charges at dawn (If Zack forgets to roll this at dawn he will not get the charges back)
				</list>
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, armor</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">127</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">15 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mantle of Avari" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MANTLE_AVARI">
		<description>
			<p>
				This midnight-blue cloak bears the embroidered symbol of Aureon subtly stitched into its lining, so faint it's barely visible unless caught in firelight.
				The mantle once belonged to Master Avari, Tug’s former mentor, and was thought lost during the fall of the monastery. It is heavier than it appears, and its fabric occasionally shifts as though breathing.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p><b>While wearing this mantle, you gain the following benefits:</b></p>
			<list>
				<li>While wearing medium or heavy armor, your Armor Class increases by 1.</li>
				<li>When a creature you can see targets you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to cause the mantle to lash out, making a melee weapon attack against the attacker:<br/>
					<b>+ WIS to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + your Wisdom modifier bludgeoning damage.</b><br/>
					You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1) per long rest.</li>
				<li>If damage would reduce you to 0 hit points but not kill you outright, you are instead reduced to 1 hit point. 
					The mantle flares with radiant energy as its threads bind your wounds, holding you together by sheer divine will.
					Once this ability is used, it cannot be used again until you finish a long rest.</li>
			</list>
			<br/>
			<p>
				The cloak cannot speak, but can communicate emotionally with its wearer—warmth, tightness, vibrations, or a sense of direction during conflict.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, armor, radiant, reaction, reach</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">15 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare (Cursed)</set>
			<set name="requirements">Cleric or Paladin</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Gloves of the Manticore" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MANTI_GLOVES">
		<description>
			<p>
				These leather gloves are embedded with sharp manticore claws extending over the knuckles.
				The claws have been polished and enchanted to be razor sharp, providing extra damage with unarmed strikes.
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong>Claws of the Beast:</strong>
				while attuned, the gauntlets allow for creatures that roll a die when they make unarmed strikes (such as the monk), 
				to increase the size of their damage die by one (maximum 1d12) when they make unarmed strikes with a hand equipped with the gauntlets.
				Otherwise the gauntlets allow the wearer to make unarmed attacks with the manticore claws, dealing 1D6 + strength slashing damage.
			</p>
			
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Gauntlet, monk, unarmed</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">20 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">arms</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Starlight Cloak" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_STARLIGHT_CLOAK">
		<description>
			<p>
				This cloak shimmers with a silver hue and appears as if it's woven from starlight itself. When worn, it grants you an aura of calm control.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				When wearing this cloak you gain an additional +1 bonus to AC. You feel the cloak is not revealing all magic to you currently
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, armor</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">224</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">10 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Cloak of the Netherking" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_NETHER_CLOAK">
		<description>
			<p>
				The mantle is made of shimmering violet threads that shift like liquid silk, with fractured sigils glowing faintly along its hems. 
				When worn by Taris the robe’s fragments coil around his frame like an incomplete cocoon; regal yet broken, like its master’s legacy.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				Your weapon attacks that deal slashing damage score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				When you trigger a Wild Magic Surge, you may roll twice and choose either result.
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, armor</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1900</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">10 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Earth-Crusher Boots" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_EARTH_BOOTS">
		<description>
			<p>
				These boots have proficiency bonus number of charges and regains all charges at the end of a long rest. While you wear these boots, 
				you can take an attack action to stomp the earth, 
				expending one charge and causing a shattering of earthin a 10 ft radius.
				<br/>
				Every creature caught in this radius other than you must make a (DC8 + proficiency + strength modifier dexterity) saving throw or take 2d6 bludgeoning damage and fall prone 
				or take half as much damage and not fall prone on a successful one.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Barbarian, Boots</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">20 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Barbarian">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1500</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Revenant Mala" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_REVENANT_MALA">
		<description>
			<p>
				A creature attuned to these blood-red prayer beads may not spend hit dice to recover HP. 
				Instead, an attuned creature may spend one minute in meditation to heal themselves up to half their hit point maximum.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Barbarian, neck</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">20 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Prayer Beads</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1500</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature who has died and been resurrected">true </set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Aureonic Garb" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_AUREON_GARB">
		<description>
			<p>
				These robes are white with golden inlays along its seams. It shines with a divine light when worn by a true follower of Aureon
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Barbarian, neck</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">20 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Prayer Beads</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1500</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature who has died and been resurrected">true </set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom:score:add" value="1" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Winter Wolf Hide" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_WINTER_HIDE">
		<description>
			<p>
				This thick, magically preserved hide is taken from a powerful Winter Wolf.
				The hide seems to subtly shift and ripple, as if the spirit of the wolf still stirs within it.
				It retains a chilling aura and a faint, wild scent. When you attune to this hide it conforms to fit over your armour, granting the following benefits:
			</p>

			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Cold Resistance.</strong> You gain resistance to cold damage.
			</p>

			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Snow Camouflage.</strong> While in snowy terrain, you gain advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide.
			</p>

			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Keen Senses</strong> You gain advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.
			</p>

			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Winter's Fury</strong> When you make a melee weapon attack, you can use a bonus action to unleash a blast of freezing wind. If the attack hits, the target takes an additional 4D6 cold damage.
				Additionally, a 15-foot cone of freezing wind erupts from the target's space.
				All other creatures within the cone, except the target, must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 4D6 cold damage.
				<br> If the initial attack misses, the target must make the DC 14 Dexterity saving throw as well, taking 4D6 cold damage on a failed save.</br>
				<br>Once you used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</br>
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="medium exotic fateweaver">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">5000</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a fighter or barbarian">true </set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Fragment of Moonlight" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MOONLIT_FRAGMENT">
		<description>
			<p>
				A small, radiant shard of light, cool to the touch. It grants you the ability to cast <em>Bless</em> once without expending a spell slot ONCE.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Cleric, Magic</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">20 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Crystal Shard</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1500</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="">false </set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Stormstride Boots" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_STORM_BOOTS">
		<description>
			<p>
				These sleek boots, fashioned from cobalt-tinted leather and adorned with faintly glowing streaks of blue, 
				have been irrevocably transformed by their long residence in an unknown Arcanist's citadel, the Stormspire
				Over a century and a half the Citadel's crackling aura of storm magic seeped into the leather, infusing the boots with raw elemental power.
				Now the air around them hums faintly with static electricity, and their soles leave faint scorch marks on the ground when worn by an attuned creature, 
				as if the wearer carries a piece of the storm wherever they go.
			</p>
			
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Charged.</strong> These boots have 3 charges, and they regain 1D3 expended charges at dawn. You can expend a charge to use one of the following features:
				<list>
					<strong>Stride the Lightning.</strong> When you cast a spell that deals thunder or lightning damage, you can entwine yourself into the spell's power as a bonus action. 
					You teleport to an unoccupied space either within the spell's area of effect or adjacent to the spell's target.
				</list>
				<list>
					<strong>Bolt Dash.</strong> You can take the dash action as a bonus action. At the end of your turn if you took the bolt dash ability, creatures of your choice within 30 feet must make a DC 14 wisdom saving throw. 
					On a failed save, a creature takes 3D8 thunder damage. On a success, they take half as much damage.
				</list>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Cleric, Magic</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2500</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">7 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Boots</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1500</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster meditating in a thunderstorm">true </set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mist" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MIST">
		<description>
			<p>
				This coat seems to be held together by crystalline formations across the seams. It eminates a mystical, protective fog. It has 3 charges that are regained every day at dawn.
			</p>
			
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Wilful Mist.</strong> Mist gathers around you, created by your presence: you can add your Charisma modifier to Dexterity (Stealth) checks while wearing the coat. 
				Additionally you can use an action to expend 2 charges to let your body partially dissolve into mist, raising your AC by 2 for 1 minute.
			</p>
			
			<p class="indent">
				<strong>Blinding Presence.</strong> You can use an action and expend 1 charge to send a plume of mist to hinder a foe: 
				they must make a Dexterity saving throw or be blinded until the end of their next turn, when the plume dissipates.
				The save DC is equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your charisma modifier.
			</p>
			
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="10">10 lb</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Amethyst of Regeneration" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_REGEN_AMETHYST">
		<description>
			<p>
				A necklace with a single large and magical amethyst. 
				Once per short rest, when the wearer takes damage, they can use their reaction to heal themselves for 1D8 + 2 and get temporary hit points equal to half the amount rolled to heal.
			</p>

			<p class="indent">
				<em>"As the battle rages on, Taris was barely able to stand, his armour dented and bloodied, but with one hand clutching the amethyst around their neck, 
					they manage to summon the strength to heal their wounds and continue the fight."</em> Recollection of the crown wars by Archmage Malazar.
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">3500</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Malazar's Tome of Constellations" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MALSTAR_TOME">
		<description>
			<p>
				This elegant tome has maps of constellations and corresponding poems about them. The Tome of Constellations is enchanted by one <em>Apprentice Malazar.</em>
				The tome allows the attuned user to cast the spell Guiding Bolt once per day. 
				Additionally, they have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to navigate outdoors at night.
			</p>

			<p class="indent">
				While holding the tome, the user can use an actions to speak the name of a constellation listed below, revealing a starry image of the constellation in the air. 
				You can only use one of the listed spells per short rest.
			</p>
			
			<p class ="indent">
				<list>
				<strong>Aureon's Guiding Sigil.</strong> While holding the tome, the user can use an action to summon Aureon's Sigil that hangs above them for 1 minute, illuminating 30 feet around the user. 
					You gain advantage on saving throws against magical effects and any radiant damage dealt by you gain an extra 1D6 damage during this time.
				</list>
			</p>

			<p class ="indent">
				<list>
					<strong>Ilmater's Healing Cerulean.</strong> While holding the tome, the user can use an action to summon a spectral Swan for 1 minute. 
					The swan sings a soothing melody, causing all allies within 30ft are cured of non magic diseases or conditions. Additionally, they regain 1d6 points of health until the swan disappears.
				</list>
			</p>

			<p class ="indent">
				<list>
					<strong>Moradin's Steadfast Anvil.</strong> While holding the tome, the user can use an action to summon a spectral anvil for 1 minute.
					You gain temporary hit points equal to your level and for the next minute you gain advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed.
				</list>
			</p>

			<p class ="indent">
				<list>
					<strong>Mystryl's Enchanted Pheonix.</strong> While holding the tome, the user can use an action to summon a spectral Pheonix which streaks upwards into the air before diving to a target you can see. 
					The pheonix explodes in a burst of enchanted flame in a 10-foot radius. The targets make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw, on a failure they take 6D6 fire damage or half as much on a success.
				</list>
			</p>

		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">3500</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
