<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>

	<info>
		<name>Weapons</name>
		<description>
			
		</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.16">
			<file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/dungeon-masters-guide/items/items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Shadowsteel Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_SHADOWSTEEL_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>
				Forged in the heart of the Umbral Forge, the <em>Shadowsteel Sword</em> is a longsword infused with dark energies that draw strength from shadows. The blade absorbs ambient light, dimming its surroundings when drawn.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				The <em>Shadowsteel Sword</em> is a magic, sentient weapon that grants a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. When attacking a creature in dim light or darkness, the sword deals an additional 2d8 necrotic damage.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">While the sword is on your person, you gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, the range increases by 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				Once per long rest, as an action, you can cast <i>shadow blade</i> (save DC 16) from the sword. The sword regains the ability to cast this spell at the next dawn.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<i>
					<b>Sentience.</b>
				</i> The <em>Shadowsteel Sword</em> is a sentient neutral evil weapon with an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 18. It has darkvision out to a range of 120 feet and can communicate telepathically with its wielder.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<i>
					<b>Personality.</b>
				</i> The sword seeks to be wielded by those who walk in the shadows and thrive in the darkness. It encourages its wielder to shun the light and embrace the night, whispering temptations to seek power in darkness.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Fang Blade of the Manticore" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_MANTI_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>
				Forged from manticore fangs, the blade is translucent bone-white with a wickedly sharp edge, it feels unnaturally warm to the touch.
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong>Venomous Strikes:</strong> The blade can deliver a dose of manticore venom on a hit, adding 1d6 poison damage. The poison lasts for 1 hour once applied. Charges are regained after a long rest.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Dent's Greatsword" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_DENT_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>
				This <em>Greatsword</em> is a magical sword blessed by dumb barbarians.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">
				You have a +1 bonus to being gay.
			</p>
			<p class="indent">As a reaction when a creature within 5 feet of you takes damage, you can cry as a free action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Dreadsong" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_DREADSONG">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					“Its blade gleams black as obsidian, with a ripple of crimson streaking across the length of the edge.
					The hilt is wrapped in blackened leather, cracked and worn. 
					The pommel holds a faintly glowing ruby.”
				</em>
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<em>Dreadsong</em> is a magic, sentient weapon that grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. For now...
			</p>
			<p>
				<i>
					<b>Sentience.</b>
				</i><em>Dreadsong</em> is a sentient, Chaotic Evil weapon with an Intelligence of 16, a Wisdom of 13, and a Charisma of 14. The item has Hearing and darkvision out to 120 ft, can speak, read, and understand Common, Dwarven and Netherese. 
				In addition, the item can communicate telepathically with any character that carries or wields it.
			</p>
			
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Manticore Crossbow" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_WHIZZ_CROSSBOW">
		<description>
			<p>
				Forged by expert dwarven craftsmen, the Crossbow of the Manticore is a deadly weapon fashioned from the remains of a slain manticore. 
				Its frame is reinforced with manticore bones and sinew, and the bolts are enchanted to mimic the creature’s fearsome spiked tail. 
				A small but fierce aura of predatory magic radiates from it, granting the wielder a taste of the manticore’s fierce power.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<strong>Manticore's Fury:</strong> When you make a ranged attack with this crossbow, you can activate the Manticore’s Fury ability. 
				You may expend one of three charges to unleash a flurry of spectral spikes alongside the bolt. 
				If the attack hits, it deals an additional 2d6 piercing damage, as ghostly spines strike the target.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				The crossbow regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Crossbow, Light, manticore</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Crossbow, Light">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_LIGHT||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Alchemists' Reprise" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_ALCHEMIST_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>
				A thin opaque bottle, meant for use when the carrier becomes unarmed. Upon activation, the blue sludge in the vial extends out and becomes a one handed blade, with the vial itself as the handle. 
				Deals 2d8 in poison damage, and evaporates after 5 turns.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Sword, Alchemy</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Weapon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES </set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Verity" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_VERITY">
		<description>
			<p>
				Shimmering with ethereal moonlight, the flames that wreath this blade have no heat to them, burning falsehoods instead of flesh. Don’t let the cold glow fool you, though. The truth can hurt more than the hottest fire.
				<br/>
				This item has <strong>1d4</strong> charges and regains <strong>1d4</strong> expended charges daily at dawn.
				<br/>
				<strong>Spells.</strong> While this weapon is on your person, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it (save DC 13): faerie fire (1 charge), moonbeam (2 charges), or zone of truth (2 charges).
				<br/>
				<strong>Revealing Light.</strong> When you hit a creature with this weapon on your turn, you can expend up to 2 charges to envelop the creature in ethereal flames. 
				If you do, any illusion and transmutation spells that the creature is concentrating on or affected by immediately end, 
				provided they are of a level equal to or lower than the number of charges expended.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Sword, rapier</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Weapon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Rapier </set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Javelin of Impalement" type="Magic Item" source="Wardens of Faerûn" id="ID_CUSTOM_JAVELIN_IMPALEMENT">
		<description>
			<p>
				This javlelin is a sleep metal rod with a razor-sharp point. It feels heavy in your hand, but despite it's weight it's surprisingly easy to throw.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<strong>Razor Sharp.</strong> You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<strong>Impale.</strong> When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this javelin, 
				the target must succeed on a DC 15 strength saving throw or become impaled by the javelin, 
				taking an extra 1d6 piercing damage and becoming restrained until the javelin is removed. 
				The javelin pins the target to the ground or any solid surface behind it, preventing the target from moving unless it breaks free.
				<br/>
				As an action, the impaled creature can attempt to free itself from the javelin by making a DC15 Strength (Athletics) check. 
				On a success, the creature is no longer restrained and can move normally but takes 1d6 slashing damage as a javelin tears through its flesh.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>
				<strong>Recall.</strong> As a bonus action, you can speak the javelin's command word and cause it to return to your hand. Provided that you are within 100 ft of it and have a free hand.
				 If the javelin is impaling a creature, the creature takes 1d6 slashing damage as the javelin pulls free from it.
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong>High Ground.</strong> If you are at least 5 ft higher than your target when you throw this javelin, you deal an additional 1d6 piercing damage for every 5 feet of height difference.
				 Up to a maximum of 3d6. This damage is added after applying the impalement effect.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Sword, rapier</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Weapon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Javelin</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
</elements>
